<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>kubernetes - Tag - </title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/kubernetes/</link>
        <description>kubernetes - Tag - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:44:24 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/kubernetes/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Packet Capture using tcpdump on Kubernetes Pods in Azure AKS</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/packet-capture-tcpdump-kubernetes-pods-azure/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:44:24 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/packet-capture-tcpdump-kubernetes-pods-azure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Assuming the target containers can actually install new software (apt install is available) what follows is a quick and very dirty method to run tcpdump on k8s/AKS containers in Azure.
Install some needed utilities Use whatever pod label is required to target the right pods.
kubectl get pods -l &lt;LABEL&gt; -o name | xargs -I{} kubectl exec {} -- apt-get -y update kubectl get pods -l &lt;LABEL&gt; -o name | xargs -I{} kubectl exec {} -- apt-get -y install tcpdump screen psmisc rclone Check kubectl get pods -l &lt;LABEL&gt; -o name | xargs -I{} kubectl exec {} -- tcpdump --version Start tcpdump in a screen Use whatever tcpdump &lt;FILTER&gt; here as needed.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Kibaba Authentication using OAuth2 Proxy in Kubernetes</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/kibaba-oauth-kubernetes/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 12:34:50 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/kibaba-oauth-kubernetes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[NOTE: There appears to be a bug with Kibanas impersonation features, and SIEM detection rules (and possibly elswhere): https://github.com/elastic/kibana/issues/74828
 Recently I had reason to want to integrate Kibana with Azure Active Directory for authentication. This might be easily possible if you have a commercial license with Elastic, but this wasn&rsquo;t the case this time.
After a little bit of research I found this article, from February 2017:
User Impersonation with X-Pack: Integrating Third Party Auth with Kibana]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
