<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>logstash - Tag - </title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/logstash/</link>
        <description>logstash - Tag - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 07:39:19 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/logstash/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Using Elasticsearch Upserts to Combine Multiple Event Lines Into One</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/using-elasticsearch-upserts-to-combine-multiple-event-lines-into-one/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 07:39:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/using-elasticsearch-upserts-to-combine-multiple-event-lines-into-one/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Note This approach is probably not appropriate for high volume / high throughput events. It required in my case quite a lot of Logstash parsing, and Elasticsearch doc_as_upsert use, both of which will have a significant performance penalty. For low throughput use it works fine.
 Sometimes log sources split logically grouped events into separate lines, and sometimes those logically grouped event lines are mixed into the same log file with actual singular line events.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Event Threat Enrichment using Logstash and Minemeld</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/event-threat-enrichment-logstash-minemeld/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 09:22:36 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/event-threat-enrichment-logstash-minemeld/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[At my work we use the Elastic Stack for quite a few things, but one of the more recent-ish &ldquo;official&rdquo; roles is as our SIEM. Elastic introduced SIEM specific funcationality to Kibana a few releases ago, around 7.4 if I rembember correctly.
One of the features that the Elastic Stack doesn&rsquo;t really support well (yet) is an enrichment system. They did introduce an elasticsearch side enrichment system in 7.5, but in my opinionn theres a few problems with it:]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
