<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>elasticsearch on </title>
    <link>robrankin.github.io/tags/elasticsearch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in elasticsearch on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 12:34:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="robrankin.github.io/tags/elasticsearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kibaba Authentication using OAuth2 Proxy in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>robrankin.github.io/posts/kibaba-oauth-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 12:34:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>robrankin.github.io/posts/kibaba-oauth-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had reason to want to integrate Kibana with Azure Active Directory for authentication. This might be easily possible if you have a commercial license with Elastic, but this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case this time.
After a little bit of research I found this article, from February 2017:
User Impersonation with X-Pack: Integrating Third Party Auth with Kibana
Obviously it&amp;rsquo;s starting to get a little long in the tooth, but as long as user impersonation is still supported, the basic outline should work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing ElasticSearch to it&#39;s knees</title>
      <link>robrankin.github.io/posts/elasticsearch-gc-and-field-mapping-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 17:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>robrankin.github.io/posts/elasticsearch-gc-and-field-mapping-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Bringing ElasticSearch to it&amp;rsquo;s knees ElasticSearch is a bloody fantastic, scalable, distributed, Lucense based search system.
At Bede Gaming we&amp;rsquo;re currently using it primarily for log collection/searching, one of the more common implementations of the ELK stack (ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana). We&amp;rsquo;re also looking to use it more front line roles within the Bede Gaming platform.
Our current statistics look something like this:
 15 days of indexes online 120 days of previous indexes offline Approx 40GB of event data per day Approx 600GB of events online (last 15 days) Approx 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>