<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - </title>
        <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 10:21:48 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Modsecurity, DetectionOnly and enforcing select rules</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/modsecurity-detectiononly-and-enforcing-select-rules/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 10:21:48 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/modsecurity-detectiononly-and-enforcing-select-rules/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently had a reason to want to achieve the following:
 ModSecurity globally in DetectionOnly mode (not enforcing rules, just logging)  Continue to operate the CRS in DetectionOnly mode.   For a specific ruleset:  Enforcing a default deny on inbound requests to an API. Enforcing allow rules for specific API routes and methods of the API    So I wanted all of our inbound CRS rules to continue to work in DetectionOnly mode, while I had a custom set of rules that would deny all access, with a set of whitelists to specific methods/paths.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Alerting using SIEM Detections and ElastAlert</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/alerting-using-siem-detections-and-elastalert/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 08:32:41 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/alerting-using-siem-detections-and-elastalert/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ElasticSearch SIEM Detections and Alerts and Actions are quite useful features, except for the fact that actual alerting is behind a license paywall. So while both of these features can run rules, check for conditions, and record the results in an index, neither of them actually provide alerting support.
Alerting requires a Gold License, which if alerting is the only thing you want, is an excessive cost.
If you can&rsquo;t move off ElasticSearch to OpenSearch, which has Alerting available for free, you can use tools such as ElastAlert21to handle the Alerting requirements.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Using Elasticsearch Upserts to Combine Multiple Event Lines Into One</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/using-elasticsearch-upserts-to-combine-multiple-event-lines-into-one/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 07:39:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/using-elasticsearch-upserts-to-combine-multiple-event-lines-into-one/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Note This approach is probably not appropriate for high volume / high throughput events. It required in my case quite a lot of Logstash parsing, and Elasticsearch doc_as_upsert use, both of which will have a significant performance penalty. For low throughput use it works fine.
 Sometimes log sources split logically grouped events into separate lines, and sometimes those logically grouped event lines are mixed into the same log file with actual singular line events.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Shell script, Azure Storage using a Service Principle</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/shell-script-azure-storage-using-a-service-principle/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 08:19:21 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/shell-script-azure-storage-using-a-service-principle/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Needed something in shell to upload files to an Azure Storage account. Hopefully its useful for others, so put it up on Github here ( https://github.com/robrankin/bash-azure-storage )]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Event Threat Enrichment using Logstash and Minemeld</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/event-threat-enrichment-logstash-minemeld/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 09:22:36 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/event-threat-enrichment-logstash-minemeld/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[At my work we use the Elastic Stack for quite a few things, but one of the more recent-ish &ldquo;official&rdquo; roles is as our SIEM. Elastic introduced SIEM specific funcationality to Kibana a few releases ago, around 7.4 if I rembember correctly.
One of the features that the Elastic Stack doesn&rsquo;t really support well (yet) is an enrichment system. They did introduce an elasticsearch side enrichment system in 7.5, but in my opinionn theres a few problems with it:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Querying Cylance Protect Api From Shell</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/querying-cylance-protect-api-from-shell/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 17:32:50 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/querying-cylance-protect-api-from-shell/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[We use Cylance as our AV type protection. They&rsquo;re one of the better solutions I&rsquo;ve seen, but theres some strange gaps in my opinion. There doesn&rsquo;t seem to be a built in method for alerting. One of the things we&rsquo;d like to be able to alert on is when a devices goes &ldquo;offline&rdquo;, and apparently this information is not provided through Cylance&rsquo;s syslog output. It is however available from their API.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Kibaba Authentication using OAuth2 Proxy in Kubernetes</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/kibaba-oauth-kubernetes/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 12:34:50 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/kibaba-oauth-kubernetes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[NOTE: There appears to be a bug with Kibanas impersonation features, and SIEM detection rules (and possibly elswhere): https://github.com/elastic/kibana/issues/74828
 Recently I had reason to want to integrate Kibana with Azure Active Directory for authentication. This might be easily possible if you have a commercial license with Elastic, but this wasn&rsquo;t the case this time.
After a little bit of research I found this article, from February 2017:
User Impersonation with X-Pack: Integrating Third Party Auth with Kibana]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Elasticsearch Provided Name and ILM</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/elasticsearch-provided-name/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 10:43:51 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/elasticsearch-provided-name/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[As I was learning a little about ElasticSearch&rsquo;s ILM (Index Lifecycle Management) feature, I ran across a parameter called provided_name when examining an index.
A bit of searching turned up the this Github issue, but it doesn&rsquo;t really explain where it comes from.
A bit more searching led me here.
So provided_name is a method of templating index names it seems, using date math as explained in the documentation.
Just make sure to HTML encode the index name, as per the example from the documentation:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Puppet Module for FoundationDB</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/puppet-module-for-foundationdb/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 16:30:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/puppet-module-for-foundationdb/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[FoundationDB has been purchased by Apple, and is no longer a product. Apple will be cancelling all support contracts and apprently not continuing to offer FDB for sale. Therefore this module is of course deprecated and no longer supported (at least by me!).
 Here at Bede we&rsquo;ve been using FoundationDB for some time, and are basically in love with it. Fully distributed, ACID compliant transactions? Yes please. It&rsquo;s fast, it scales, it&rsquo;s reliable and redundant.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Modelling an nginx Application Proxy using Puppet and Hiera</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/modelling-an-nginx-application-proxy-using-puppet-and-hiera/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 15:53:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/modelling-an-nginx-application-proxy-using-puppet-and-hiera/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Goal To model nginx configurations in Hiera, extracting those configurations from the Puppet DSL, and create a Puppet Profile to combine that with the nginx module.
Links Puppet Docs  Puppet Resource Abstraction Layer Puppet create_resources Scoping Namespacing  Puppet Roles/Profiles  Craig Dunn, Designing Puppet Talk End to End Roles and Profiles Example Puppet Workflow Part 1 Puppet Workflow Part 2  Hiera  Puppet Labs Hiera Docs Passing Variables to Hiera  nginx Module  jfryman nginx Puppet Module  nginx  nginx Project Page  Requirements Within nginx we need to define a set of nginx &ldquo;server&rdquo; contexts with the same set of &ldquo;location&rdquo; contexts in each &ldquo;server&rdquo;.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
