<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>alerting - Tag - </title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/alerting/</link>
        <description>alerting - Tag - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:42:34 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/alerting/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Storing Github Org Auditlogs in Elasticsearch</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/github-org-auditlogs-elasticsearch/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:42:34 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/github-org-auditlogs-elasticsearch/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I had a need to generate an alert when someone overrode a Branch Protection setting. To do this I decided to pull some of the GitHub Auditlog into Elasticsearch.
Theres a GitHub API client written in sh, called ok.sh, which can be found here. At the time it didn&rsquo;t support querying the Org Auditlog, so I PR&rsquo;d that here.
Once the PR was in place, I wrote a Dockerfile to create a container to deploy on Kubernetes.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Alerting using SIEM Detections and ElastAlert2</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/alerting-using-siem-detections-and-elastalert/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 08:32:41 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/alerting-using-siem-detections-and-elastalert/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ElasticSearch SIEM Detections and Alerts and Actions are quite useful features, except for the fact that actual alerting is behind a license paywall. So while both of these features can run rules, check for conditions, and record the results in an index, neither of them actually provide alerting support.
Alerting requires a Gold License, which if alerting is the only thing you want, is an excessive cost.
If you can&rsquo;t move off ElasticSearch to OpenSearch, which has Alerting available for free, you can use tools such as ElastAlert21 to handle the Alerting requirements.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
