<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>cloud - Tag - </title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/cloud/</link>
        <description>cloud - Tag - </description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:42:34 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/cloud/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Storing GitHub Org Auditlogs in Elasticsearch</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/github-org-auditlogs-elasticsearch/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:42:34 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/github-org-auditlogs-elasticsearch/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I had a need to generate an alert when someone overrode a Branch Protection setting. To do this I decided to pull some of the GitHub Auditlog into Elasticsearch.
Theres a GitHub API client written in sh, called ok.sh, which can be found here. At the time it didn&rsquo;t support querying the Org Auditlog, so I PR&rsquo;d that here.
Once the PR was in place, I wrote a Dockerfile to create a container to deploy on Kubernetes.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Azure Translation Services with Elasticsearch and Logstash</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/azure-translation-services-elasticsearch-logstash/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 06:54:40 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/azure-translation-services-elasticsearch-logstash/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently had a need to parse some XML into Elasticsearch, specifically some CERT RSS feeds. Logstash has an RSS input, but it&rsquo;s a bit basic, and doesn&rsquo;t provide any language indications if the RSS feed includes them. One of the feeds I&rsquo;m using can be various languages per item, and many others are non-english entirely.
Since this would be parsing the same RSS feeds repeatedly, I need a predictable Document ID, so I can re-insert / upsert the item, and not create a new document every time the RSS feed is parsed.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
